<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<RxML>
<TEXT><![CDATA[
<gender>Female</gender>
<age>25-34</age>
<treatment_length>6 months to less than 1 year</treatment_length>
<satisfaction>1</satisfaction>
<effectiveness>1</effectiveness>
<condition>Condition: Birth Control</condition>
<comment>You guys have NO idea how relieved I am to read most of these reviews. I was put On Junel about 6 months ago after having been on Mircette for almost 2 years. I was switched due to some mood problems around what would normally be ovulation time but trust me I would FAR prefer that then the side effects of Junel. Starting about 2-3 months ago I started getting what I thought was just PMS-type symptoms but it very quickly turned into severe depression. I had absolutely no sex drive whatsoever. I didn't even want to think about it. I felt completely hopeless sad and just out of it and not myself. I would be in the middle of my workday or watching TV or any other random activity and I would suddenly find myself thinking about the most ridiculous things like "Why should I bother to do this and that or whatever for the future? I'm just gonna get old and die." Sounds stupid but it was horrific. And it was constant. I was crying nearly every day for no reason at all. I didn't even need something to set it off. I would just cry many times as soon as I got into bed and bawl my eyes out until I finally fell asleep. I was barely getting any rest because of this so I was sleeping half my days away. It was really truly awful. I just stopped taking them a week ago today and the mood has improved immensely. Not at 100% just yet but I hope to be there soon. Definitely going to the doctor to see if there's anything else I can try ASAP. I can't really comment on how effective it was against pregnancy because you couldn't have paid me enough money to have sex while on it. Thank you SO MUCH to everyone who posted on here. I feel so much more hopeful now knowing that chances are I'm not going insane and that it was just that stupid pill!</comment>
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S6" spans="1157~1163" text="crying" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S7" spans="1260~1263" text="cry" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S10" spans="1305~1309" text="bawl" category="" condition="" change="" area="" happened="" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S8" spans="1406~1432" text="sleeping half my days away" category="ENERGY" condition="" change="decrease" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S9" spans="1748~1794" text="couldn't have paid me enough money to have sex" category="SEXUAL" condition="libido" change="decrease" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S0" spans="672~682" text="depression" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S1" spans="701~713" text="no sex drive" category="SEXUAL" condition="libido" change="decrease" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S2" spans="782~790" text="hopeless" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S3" spans="791~794" text="sad" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S5" spans="804~813" text="out of it" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<SIDE_EFFECT id="S4" spans="818~828" text="not myself" category="EMOTIONAL" condition="mood" change="worse" area="" happened="yes" comment="" />
<MODIFIER id="M2" spans="1164~1180" text="nearly every day" intensity="" comment="" />
<MODIFIER id="M3" spans="1264~1274" text="many times" intensity="" comment="" />
<MODIFIER id="M0" spans="665~671" text="severe" intensity="high" comment="" />
<MODIFIER id="M1" spans="771~781" text="completely" intensity="high" comment="" />
</TAGS>
</RxML>